Bronson Wilburn

Senior Full-Stack Engineer

Texas, United States bronsonwilburn@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Professional software engineer specializing in both frontend and backend with 8 years of experience. Contributed on an array of projects from small to large for diverse industries.

Solid knowledge of various frameworks and several programming languages. Strong problem solving / root cause analysis skills, ability to identify scalability, and improve system processes.

SKILLS

React/Redux, Next.js, Node.js, JavaScript / TypeScript, Vue, Angular, Flask, Django, Django Rest Framework, Python, Laravel, PHP, Express.js, AWS, Rest, GraphQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.

EXPERIENCE

Devvela | | Chicago, US | Remote

Senior full Stack developer - July 2021 - January 2023

- Built reusable components and responsive pages using Tailwind CSS to reduce over 3 months' development time.
- Covered 95 % of automation testing following TDD.
- Worked directly with the CTO and collaborated actively with the product and UI/UX team.
- Built an MVP using React and Django in 3 months.
- Accelerated the loading time by 35% for the data analyzing website by implementing Code-Splitting and Optimizing performance.
- Dramatically improved the user experience for over 10,000 users by optimizing code and refactoring a legacy web app with jQuery to using React and Redux.
- Tech Used: React, React Testing Library, TypeScript, GraphQL, AWS amplify, S3, lambda, Tailwind CSS, Django.

Josh Software Inc | Plano, US | Remote

Full stack Developer - March 2017 - June 2020

- Rewrote all class-based components to functional components with hooks and implemented the Context API for global storage.
- Wrote 230 individual tests across 80 test suites to reach 90% code coverage.
- Structured several internal systems comprising production workflow tracking, as wellas
 designed and developed custom REST APIs and GraphQL schemas using Node,
 Express and Apollo.
- Developed a real-time chat application for specific company usage using Go, gRPC, and React. It reduced the business time by 10% and much paperwork.
- Participated in building and deploying a new GrowHealthy.com platform that
 integrates different systems and APIs such as Twilio APIs, Onfleet APIs, Zendesk,
 GCP, Google Maps APIs, and many others to support the logic of processing
 customer orders.
- Participated in building and deploying seven different websites under ayrwellness.com brand and integrated them with provider services and APIs.
- Tech Used: React, Laravel, PHP, Angular, Docker, TypeScript, Express.js, GraphQL, Socket.io.

Enterprise Informatics Inc | San Diego, California | Remote

Frontend Developer - October 2015 - March 2017

- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed using React.
- Improved performance of the webpage by modularizing components and building tailor-specific GraphQL queries for each module to decrease bandwidth payload and increase shareability.
- Developed user interfaces with Vue.js, which improved user satisfaction by 28%.
- Updated HTML / JavaScript based legacy platform into React/Redux based application.
- Implemented user-facing homepage with JavaScript, and React increasing promotion email sign-up rate by over 6%, generating \$400,000 in revenue annually.
- Tech used: React, Redux, Jest, Cypress, Vue.js, Material UI, Node.js, Laravel, Ant Design, jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, CI, JIRA, Git.

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University, - BS in Computer Science